Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
"Beware of
the Jabberwock, my son.
"The jaws that bite,
"the claws that catch!
"Beware the Jubjub bird
"and shun
the frumious Bandersnatch.
"He took his vorpal sword
in hand
"Long time the manxome foe
he sought.
"The Jabberwock,
with eyes of flame
"Came whiffling through
the tulgey wood."
Oh, hi, Rachel.
Mom wants Angela
to get ready for bed,
and she says it's time
for Charles to go home.
Go brush your teeth, Angela.
It's just a book.
People don't actually
go through mirrors.
Here, play a song
on your music box,
it will make you feel better.
So, I was thinking,
my dad said I could...
borrow a car
from the dealership.
There's this place
that people go to.
And what would we do?
Um...
Angela?
Are you almost done
in there?
Angela?
Angela!
What is it?
This doesn't look so bad,
does it?
I'm not sure
what's going on.
I spoke to your aunt
just two two days ago
and told her
we'd be here this morning.
Is this normal for her?
We don't know.
I don't know what we're going
to do if she's not here.
We could go back home.
Hello!
I'm Charles,
I'm a friend of Beth's.
I live down the road.
I was supposed to be here
when you arrived,
but overslept. I'm sorry.
It's all right.
You must be Olivia and Claire.
Is their aunt home?
She should be.
I was knocking and...
Well, she's a little slow
getting around.
She's, uh...
not well.
Oh.
But let's go inside,
and we'll find her.
Come on.
You've got Olivia here.
It's gonna be okay.
It should only be
a few days.
We're going to find your dad.
Just a few days.
Okay?
It's all right, Claire bear.
Everything's going
to be all right.
We're together.
Hi, you must be Beth.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry,
is everything all right?
I don't want them here.
What?
What I mean is...
I think it would be best
if you took them.
Yes, um...
that's not possible.
I thought I explained all this
to you on the phone.
Uh, who are you again?
Camilla Clark.
I worked with their mother.
Is there
some sort of problem,
- because when we talked...
- The problem is,
I don't normally
entertain visitors.
They're not just visitors,
they're your nieces.
Their mother's just died.
Your own sister.
My husband and I are moving
clear across the country
in a matter of days.
All of our things are packed.
We can't take them with us.
Not under these circumstances.
What about their father?
He's working out of
the country somewhere,
we haven't been able
to reach him.
I guess he and Rachel have been
divorced for some time?
I wouldn't know.
We've been trying
to contact him,
but we just haven't been
able to yet.
I'm sure as soon as we do,
he'll want to come straight
back to collect the girls.
In the meantime,
considering all
they've been through,
I really think
the best thing for them
is to be with family.
Don't mind your aunt.
She acts a little...
different sometimes,
but she means well.
She's a very
extraordinary person...
But she's been through
a lot in her life.
We should form a club.
Well, girls,
I'm afraid
I have to be going.
Your father will be here
soon, I'm sure.
And in the meantime,
if you girls need anything,
anything at all,
don't hesitate to call.
Okay?
I'll let myself out.
Goodbye.
This is your
Aunt Angela's room.
The one who died?
Unless you have
another Aunt Angela
no one's told me about.
It's the only other room
in the house
with a bed in it
at the moment.
So, you'll have to share.
I didn't want you
to come here.
And by your expressions...
I can only gather
that the feeling is mutual.
But you're here,
and while you are,
there are some rules
you'll need to follow.
No one in the kitchen
between mealtimes,
everyone in your rooms
by 10:00,
lights out by 11:00.
There's an elevator there,
but it's broken
and dangerous.
Stay out of it.
There is a bathroom
adjacent to your room,
so there should be no reason
for anyone to come out
until morning.
That is my study.
No one is to go in there.
This door leads
to the basement.
It stays locked at all times.
Why?
Because the basement
has rats.
Any more questions?
This... is the dining room.
The kitchen is just there.
If you hear any noises
in the night,
ignore them.
It's an old house,
and besides,
I have a tendency to sleepwalk,
so it's probably just me
bumping into something
or knocking it over.
If I see either of you
wandering the house
after hours,
there will be consequences.
Are all those rules clear?
Yes.
Claire,
do you mind asking Lucy B
if she understands the rules?
She says she does.
Since the accident,
she doesn't like
to talk to strangers.
The doctors say
it's perfectly normal
for a girl her age
who's been through...
It's a weakness.
And weakness is not good.
Well, I have some work to do.
I assume you girls
can entertain yourselves
until dinnertime?
Good.
Oh, hello.
I was just looking around.
No, it's fine.
What are you doing?
Planting some flowers.
Pansies.
You could eat these,
you know.
Do you live here?
No.
But, uh...
I do come over a lot,
to help out with things.
Like gardening?
Yes.
I suppose I enjoy
participating in the...
miracle of creating new life
in some small way.
And I never had
any children of my own,
so I guess in a small way,
I look on these
little flowers
as my children.
You might want to
get ready for dinner.
We'll be eating soon.
Okay.
Hope you girls like this.
It's actually
an African recipe.
Don't worry.
There's nothing strange in it,
it's mostly just chicken
and vegetables.
Your Aunt Beth would live
on toast and tea
if left to herself.
Well, bon appetit.
We're honored you could
tear yourself away
from your work
long enough to join us.
What is this?
It's that African stew.
You'll like it.
I got you something.
They had it.
They did.
What's that?
A book.
A late Coptic necromancy.
On the history,
it's a book on...
history.
So, what do you girls
like to do for fun?
I don't know...
Stuff.
"Stuff"?
I enjoy stuff.
Maybe once you're
settled in, we can...
find some fun stuff to do.
They're not going
to be here that long.
I know that.
But that doesn't mean
that while they're here
they can't have a good time.
So...
you two have known each
other for a long time?
Since we were kids.
Younger than you.
Yup. Everyone knew about
the Molnars around here.
Especially your Aunt Beth.
Why is that?
Because your Aunt Beth
won a very prestigious
violin competition.
Really?
When she was only ten.
Is that true?
He talks too much.
It's absolutely true
and she knows it.
Claire, you haven't
eaten anything.
You better eat.
Lucy B would like this.
It has carrots.
Come on.
See? It isn't too bad.
What's in this?
Chicken, vegetables,
some spices...
I use a little peanut butter
to thicken the sauce.
Why? Why?
Why?
Olivia?
Claire, breathe. Breathe.
Claire. Claire, breathe.
Claire, breathe.
It's okay, it's okay.
It's okay.
- What do we do? What do we do?
- Move!
She gonna be all right?
I should have told you
she has a severe peanut allergy.
I'm so sorry.
Listen to me.
Come here. Hear me.
Come to the basement.
What?
I can't.
Aunt Beth told us
not to go in there.
Go help Mommy, Claire.
Mommy?
My mommy?
Go to the basement.
How? It's locked.
I know where the key is.
Hmm?
Don't be afraid.
I'm here with you.
Move the piece on the side
and slide the top off.
Slide it down
and then the top will open.
Yes...
I don't want to.
It's okay.
Mommy...
Is that you?
Where are you?
How?
Then can I see you?
"Mirror, mirror, open wide,
"let the spirit come inside."
Mommy?
Claire?
What are you doing?
Hiding.
From what?
From Aunt Beth.
She wants to hurt me.
What are you talking about?
Aunt Beth
doesn't want to hurt you.
Come on.
Please.
Don't let her get me.
Nobody wants
to get you, Claire.
I'll show you.
We can't go in there.
What are you doing?
Here it is.
This must be
what I saw in the mirror.
How did you know about this?
Mom told me.
Hello? Mrs. Clark,
this is Olivia McCallum.
Hi, Olivia. How's it going?
We need to get out of here.
You gotta get over here, now.
What's going on?
I just found an article saying
that Aunt Beth murdered somebody.
You're not eating your food.
I'm not really that hungry.
Sorry.
Someone else,
on the other hand,
is turning into a ravenous
little tiger.
I'm glad to hear that.
I was worried about her.
You know...
I was thinking,
now that we've had a chance to get
to know each other a little better,
it might be nice for you girls
to stay a little longer.
We are family, after all.
That's very nice of you,
but I'm sure my father would
want to get us right away.
From what I've heard, your father's
pretty hard to reach right now.
Well, our friend reached him,
so it's okay.
He should be here
in a few days.
I see.
Well, maybe we should ask
Claire what she thinks.
Now that
she's feeling better.
What do you think, Claire?
Would you like to stay here,
in this house, for a while?
So...
you'd like to stay here,
instead of going with your father?
Yes.
Get out!
Get it out.
What are you doing, Claire?
I wanna get it out.
Get it out.
I want to get it out.
I want to get it out!
- I want to get it out!
- Stop that!
What's wrong with her?
I don't know.
- I'll go get Charles.
- No.
To take her
to the hospital.
How is she?
She's sleeping now.
Well, Charles brought his car.
Okay, then, I'll go get her.
There's no need to wake her.
I'll carry her down.
You go wait in the car.
Where's Claire?
She went into
the basement, didn't she?
I could see it in her eyes.
It's the same look Angela had.
No!
Get her phone.
Get her phone!
No. Get off me!
Hold her still.
Come on! Take it.
Oh, get your gun.
Okay!
Okay.
No!
Let me out!
Please!
Everything okay?
Yeah. There's been
a change of plans...
Oh, they're asleep right now,
so it's probably
not the best time.
I'm gonna
pick them up in the morning.
- Okay. Yeah.
- Travel safe.
No.
I'm up here!
Please, don't go!
Don't go! Don't go!
Don't...
She's gone.
Hey.
Come on.
Come on!
Did you call the police?
Gun.
Okay.
I found this under the...
You should leave.
You'd like that,
wouldn't you?
I know all about you.
- I don't think you know what...
- Shut up!
Go get the girls.
Go!
You try anything,
she dies.
- Where's Claire?
- She's in there.
Go get her.
Don't look at her,
just go get Claire!
You're a courageous woman.
Foolish, but courageous.
I admire that.
I don't give a shit
what you admire.
Oh, my God.
What did they do to you?
We didn't do anything to her.
- Get down there!
- You can't take her away from here.
It won't let you.
Just go!
No, I don't want to go!
- Claire, come on.
- No, you have to.
- Come on.
- No!
- No. I don't want to.
- You'll feel better soon, Claire.
No! No.
Olivia, grab her feet.
- I don't want to go. No!
- It's okay, honey.
No! No! No!
- Claire.
- I don't want to. No.
No!
I want to wait for Mommy.
Mommy's dead, Claire.
I know.
But she's coming back.
Back where?
Into the world.
Let's get out of here.
I want Lucy B.
Claire, we have to go.
Please?
- I need Lucy B.
- Okay, it's fine. Just be quick.
- All right?
- Okay.
- Hurry.
- I'll be right back.
Okay? She's gonna
go get Lucy B.
Everything's going to be okay.
Don't leave.
It's safe in here.
Where's your sister?
She's gone.
And your friend?
I was about
your same age...
when I first learned the
truth about this house.
And I can assure you,
I felt very much the same way
you do right now.
What is happening?
The first thing you need to know
is that your sister, Claire,
is completely innocent.
Everything she's doing
right now
is because of it.
"It"?
This house is inhabited by an
entity of extreme malevolence.
It's using your sister
to free itself
and get back
into the world.
Yes, it says there are
three doors.
The mirror
is the first door.
It leads to the mind.
The mind is the second door.
It leads to the body.
The body is the third door.
It leads to the world,
and to destruction.
That thing is using
your sister as a vessel.
Taking shape inside her.
Just like it did
inside Angela.
So that's why you killed her?
Yes.
But only after I saw what she
had done to our parents.
Then, it was self-defense?
Of course it was.
What else would it be?
You are not going
to kill my sister.
Of course not.
Why do you think
I came back here,
to this house,
after they released me?
To find a way
to finally defeat it.
not to kill.
Where do you think
she would be?
She won't go far.
It won't let her.
No. It needs
to keep her safe.
She'll be somewhere
in this house.
Can I ask you something?
Of course.
In the paper...
it said that you were
a person of interest
in Angela's killing.
Yeah.
That's what they said.
Well?
"Well," what?
Were you there?
Did you see Aunt Beth
kill Aunt Angela?
Yeah.
I was there.
And, no...
I didn't see your Aunt Beth
kill your Aunt Angela.
We were both there.
But it was...
me.
Me who...
But you never went
to jail.
I ran before the cops
got there.
But...
Not your aunt.
She thought if she could
just tell them the truth,
they'd believe her.
They interrogated her
for over 14 hours.
She could have implicated me
at any time.
Bargained for a better deal.
She never did.
She never even mentioned
my name.
She spent the better part
of her young adult life
in a... mental hospital.
While...
I graduated high school,
went to college,
got married,
got divorced...
I owe her my life.
There you are.
So...
Do you think
you're up for this?
Charles! Beth!
No!
Claire?
Who are you?
No. Claire?
Claire.
Claire, stop!
Stop, please!
Please.
How long till we get
this thing out of her?
Not long.
Uh, yeah. We just need something
that belongs to your sister.
Her bunny.
Perfect.
The two of you go get it.
Yeah, okay.
It should be in here.
No!
No, no, no!
No! Let me out!
Please!
No.
I'm sorry.
Get away from her.
Olivia.
What did you do to her?
We just gave her a sedative
to relax her.
Put down the knife.
- Olivia.
- Put it down!
You said you were
going to help her.
I wish I could help her.
For more than 15 years,
I have tried to find a way to help her,
and others like her.
But I failed.
You lied to me.
I had no choice.
If this thing gets out,
many more people will die.
It says in the book...
"Only through death
"will the third door
be closed."
We have to do this!
Give me the knife.
Take her out of here.
No.
Are you really gonna
let her do this?
let her kill Claire
because of something
she read in a book?
Don't listen to her.
Think!
Do you really want the death
of another little girl
in your conscience?
You know this has to be done!
There has to be another way.
There is no other way.
And you know that!
No.
I don't.
All I know
is what you've told me.
Don't be a fool!
I'm sorry.
You were always weak.
You don't know
what you're doing!
She's not evil,
you know?
She... She loved Angela,
and she loves your sister, too.
She just...
believes what she's saying.
And what about you?
What do you believe?
I... I don't know.
All I know is that when Angela
died, that thing was gone.
Well, not gone, it's...
It's back in its cage, anyway.
You're probably hungry,
I'll make you some food.
No peanut butter.
Wait.
Are you sure about this?
No. But what other choice
do we have?
Not yet!
Now!
Come on.
- Fuck!
- Come on, Claire.
Come on. Come on, come on.
Come on, Claire.
Can she take that many?
Claire.
Claire?
Come on, Claire. Please.
Come on. Claire, come on.
Wake up.
Claire, wake up.
- Wake up.
- Claire!
Wake up! Wake up. Please.
Please, wake up.
Please, Claire...
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry.
Livvy?
Claire... Claire...
My stomach hurts.
Hey.
How's she holding up?
Like you'd expect.
Stubbornly insisting
that she's right,
that we couldn't possibly
have sent that thing back
using peanut butter.
Then, how does she
explain Claire?
I don't think she can,
to be honest.
It's enough to get you by
until your dad gets back.
Beth asked me
to give it to you.
It's all right.
Take it.
I think it's the easiest way
for her to say she's sorry.
Where will you go?
Back to our old house for now.
Girls your age
shouldn't be on their own.
I think we'll survive.
Well, let me give you
a lift, anyway.
It's the least I can do.
You couldn't find her?
No.
But it's okay.
I don't need her anymore.
Great. Let's go, then.
Back door.
Claire!
Come on!
What happened?
Claire.
Olivia.
Olivia!
Olivia, come on!
This way.
This way, come on.
It stopped.
What's happening?
Wait.
I, uh... Wait, wait.
I read something here.
Wait, it's... here.
"It is possible, if their door
be not fully closed,
"in traveling from the realms
of elemental darkness,
"a spirit may become
caught between two worlds...
"tethered to their place
of origin
"until such time
as they're able
"to complete their journey."
That must be it.
That's why it still
wants Claire.
And that's why it's able
to touch us,
to affect us physically...
even though
we still can't see it.
I did see it.
And I think I heard it.
That means...
maybe we can kill it.
But we need something first.
What?
What happened?
Olivia!
There are flashlights
in the cupboard.
There's more
in the kitchen.
I can't find it.
Beth, wasn't there
a lantern in here?
Claire...
What?
Charles!
What happened?
She's gone. It took her.
Claire! Claire!
Claire!
- Claire! Claire!
- Claire!
I don't see her.
She's not here.
Claire.
The basement!
- Oh, come on.
- Claire!
- The elevator!
- No!
What?
- Charles!
- It won't open!
Say the words, Claire.
Be a good girl.
You wouldn't want to
make Mommy...
angry!
She's upstairs!
Claire!
Run, Claire!
No!
Olivia?
Claire? Claire!
Olivia!
No!
Mirror, mirror, open wide,
let the spirit come inside.
Mirror, mirror, open wide...
Let the spirit
come inside...
- Don't let her say the words.
- Mirror, mirror,
open wide.
Let the spirit come inside.
Claire, don't say the words!
Mirror, mirror,
open wide,
let this spirit come inside.
Aunt Beth, no.
Mirror, mirror, open wide...
Let this spirit come inside.
Mirror, mirror, open wide,
let this spirit come inside!
Please, no.
Aunt Beth, I can't do this.
Do it.
I can't.
No. Please, stop.
No.
Claire...
It's over. It's over.
♪ Sing with me
♪ My darling
♪ When you're feeling blue
♪ I'll always be right here
♪ Waiting for you
♪ I'll wait now
♪ Where we do
♪ If you ask me to
♪ It would be lonely
♪ If not for you
♪ Come rest your head
my sweetheart
♪ Shaking bones
♪ If darkness takes
my darling
♪ I'll light your way
back home
♪ In dust and bone we'll stay
♪ Forever we'll remain
♪ I'll find my way back
♪ To you
Can I speak to her alone?
I just want you to know
- my sister had nothing to...
- I know.
This is being reported
as a murder-suicide.
Let's get them out of here.
Livvy...
What?
Is Aunt Beth really dead?
Yeah.
But she saved us.
But we aren't gonna talk
about that to anybody, okay?
Livvy.
What?
I love you.
I love you too, Claire bear.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org